Friends, India's
number one private sector health insurance company, ICI
Lombard, recently
launched a number one plan two-three days ago. This is a
plan that no one else in the industry
currently offers.
You'll get unlimited benefits in this,
whether it's claims,
cover, or no-claim bonus. There are
many benefits here. In
a way, it's a completely customized policy, and
its premium is also very budget-friendly. So,
this plan is very beautiful. The
name of the plan is ICI Lombard's Elevate
Plan. In this video, we
'll cover this product in detail and what all
you get here. So, please
watch the video till the end.
Before we proceed further, let me introduce myself a little.
My name is
Brijendra Gautam, and you're watching ABTech
Financial Planner. For the past nine years, I've been
working in the field of insurance and mutual funds. If you have any policy or
any query, you
can contact us.  You will get the contact number and
email ID from the description box.
What is the company's profile?
ICICI Lombard is the number one health insurance company in the private sector.
Its special feature here is that
you must have seen that recently in January, the
Cashless Anyway feature was launched, so
it is passing the claims very efficiently
under the Cashless Anyway feature.
If you are not aware of this, then let me
tell you that Cashless Anyway means that even
if you go and get
treatment at their non-network hospital, your
cashless treatment will be approved there too. If we
talk about the company's claim settlement
ratio, then it is at the top, at 99.
If we talk about the Income Claim
Ratio, then it is at
78, but this is also correct. If the
Income Claim Ratio of a company comes above 50,
it means it is correct. Apart from this, let me
tell you that the company's Solve Ratio is at 2.5.  So the
profile of the company is very good, there
is no problem of any kind here, let me tell you that
here it has five such top features, in this
you are getting unlimited things and
because of these five things this plan
is very beautiful,
these features are not available in any other company right now, first of all let's
talk about unlimited cover here, in this
plan you are getting unlimited cover, that is,
your cover starts from minimum 5 lakhs here,
you can take maximum cover as much as you want, unlimited cover is also
available here, in this series the second top
feature of it is unlimited claim
amount here, let me explain this thing with an example,
suppose your base cover is of 10 lakhs in
it non claim bonus is also of 10 lakhs,
your total cover is of 20 lakhs, but
suppose due to some reason you get a major disease,
there your claim comes up to 60 lakhs, 70 lakhs, one
crore, two crores, then the company
says that here we will pay this claim of yours once in your lifetime,
okay, but this is a  There is an
add-on feature which you have to take separately. Let's
talk about the third special feature here,
that is unlimited restoration.
Most of the companies offer the benefit of unlimited restoration
here,
but even if the same person has the same illness,
you will get it here,
unlimited registration. If we talk about the fourth special feature
here, then it is limited no
claim bonus. Friends, this has come for the first time in the industry,
which is
not available with any company right now. Earlier you saw that
some companies used to give 5x, 10x here, but
this company has done away with the x feature itself. You will get the
complete unlimited no claim
bonus here. How will you get it, understand carefully.
Here, it is an additional feature, you will have to take it
as a separate rider. Now, here,
as you take this feature, suppose
you have a policy of Rs. 10 lakhs. Your policy
runs for 10 years. If you run that plan for 10 years, then
after 10 years, your
total cover will be Rs. 1 crore. Suppose you have taken this
policy.  If you continue this plan for 20 years, then
your cover cover here, your policy cover of 10 lakhs will become
2 crores. If you
continue your policy for 30 years, then the
total cover of your policy will become 3 crores.
Unlimited cover is available here,
whereas what you have to pay here is
only premium and you are getting additional cover of only 10 lakhs
here. Now its
fifth top feature is Unlimited Assurance,
this is in a way related to pre-existing diseases.
Here the company is saying that
if you have these five diseases, then
we will cover it completely after 30 days. Now
which are these five diseases, the first one is
Asthma, the second is Hypertension, the third is
Diabetes, the fourth is Hyperlipidemia and the
fifth one is Obesity. If you have any of these five
diseases, then
if you take this as a day, then after 30 days
your diseases and pre-existing diseases will be
completely covered. So friends, these were the
top five features of this company
which make this plan the most beautiful.
Apart from this  There are many more things in this
which I will tell you in the video further, you should
watch the video till the end, you will see that
in the industry there is already a company which has
come up with such features, now in the coming time
different companies will come up with similar
features, so somewhere or the other when
competition will be seen in the market, then
somewhere or the other the customer will get the benefit of it, so
let us now talk
about the basic features of this plan, so let us
start with the eligibility criteria,
here the minimum age limit is 18 years, there is
no maximum age limit, whether
your age is 70 years, 75 years, 90 years,
100 years, 125 years, even then you
can take this plan and here
you can continue it for life time, there is
no upper age restriction, let us
talk about the room rent, in
its basic plan you have been given a single
private AC room, but if
you want to take a higher category room or below this  If you want to
take a category room, then here
you have to take a separate rider whose
name is Room Modify. If you
take this rider here, then if you
want to go higher, then you can also choose A room category.
Apart from this, if you want to downgrade it, then
here you
can also take a twin sharing room. If you
take a twin sharing room here, then you will
get a discount here. If you
go to the upper category, then you will have to pay some
extra premium here.
If we talk about the cover amount in this, then
its cover here starts from 5 lakhs, 5 lakhs, 75 lakhs, 10 lakhs, 15 lakhs, 20 lakhs, 25 lakhs, 50 lakhs, 1 crore, 2 crores,
3 crores and
there is also an option of unlimited sum assured in this.
Apart from this, let's talk about pre and
post hospitalization, here
you get a time period of 90 days in pre
and 180 days for post, that is,
you get a present post of 90 and 180 days here.  If we
talk about modern treatment, then
all the modern treatments will be covered for you here, there is no
problem. If we
talk about day care procedures, then all your day care procedures will also be
covered. There is no
special list.
All the day procedures suggested by IRDA will be
covered for you. If we talk about no claim bonus,
here in the base plan,
your benefit will increase by 20% per year whether your claim comes
or not, it will not make any difference.
Your benefit will increase by 20% every year, maximum it will
go up to 100% here. But if you
want to take unlimited cover, then
you will get a separate cover for it, so that
your unlimited cover increases every year. If we
talk about domestic road ambulance, then
that too will be covered till your time. If we
talk about AYUSH, then all your
AYUSH treatments will be covered.
Domiciliary ones will be covered till the
time of death. Apart from this,
bariatric surgery is also covered at Bariatia
and that too will be covered till the time of death, but for this
you will have a 2 year guarantee.  There will be a waiting period. If we
talk about donor expenses, then donor
expenses will also be covered here till your end.
Apart from this, if we talk about
maternity cover, then you will get maternity cover
here as an add-on.
Maternity cover will also be covered up to Rs 1 lakh here, either
your end of the term is Rs 10 lakh and
you will get maximum cover up to Rs 1 lakh.
Apart from this, if we talk about new born baby
expenses, then new born
baby expenses will also be covered here,
you will get cover up to Rs 2 lakh here.
Apart from this, the vaccination cost of the new born baby, then all the
vaccinations of the first year will
also be covered here.
An important feature in its base plan is
surrogacy. This is also
considered very important in today's time,
so surrogacy will also be covered here till your end.
Apart from this,
your on-side treatment, all the expenses of the side donor will
also be
covered here. Let's talk about OPD.  For those who
wish to avail OPD services, the
B-Fit Rider is available here. Under the B-Fit Rider,
you can avail OPD services.
You will find many benefits in this plan.
You also get the facility of unlimited e-consultations.
You can get unlimited e-consultations from the doctor as much as you want.
For consumer bills, there is a Claim
Protector Rider, which you
know is always available as a separate rider.
You can also get it here as a rider, in
which you
can cover consumer bills. Along with this, you will
also get an Inflation Protector, which
you will get as a rider. If you opt for this, then
your time saved here will
increase according to inflation.
Apart from this, let us tell you that
domestic air ambulance is
not included in the base plan. However,
if you wish, you can take it as an add-on.
If we talk
about the claim protection benefit, here you will get Rs
1000 per day for a maximum of 10 days.
You get the benefit here.
Talking about annual health checkup, it is
not included in the base plan. For this also,
you will have to take a separate rider. If you
want to take it, you can take it as a rider.
Like other plans,
your critical illness is also covered here.
You can use any time cover you want for critical illness
here.
You can take it as a rider.
Apart from this, you will also get personal accident cover here,
if you need it, you can
take it as an add-on. Along with this,
you will also get compassionate cover,
which you can take as an add-on.
Along with this, if you
talk about durable equipment cover, like many
times it happens that we have to purchase some well chair etc.
for our home or
for a patient, then if you want those too,
you will get a rider for durable equipment cover,
which you can take as an add-on.
Along with this, you also get network advantage as an add-on in this plan.
You are getting this benefit, you can avail it if you want. So
here, if you go and get
treatment done in their network hospital, then
you will get a discount of 10% on the premium while buying the policy, but if you
go to a non-network hospital, then
later you will have to pay a co-pay. So,
you are looking at this thing. Now let's talk
about discounts.
Friends, let me tell you that there are many discounts available in this policy. The
main
discount here is the wellness discount.
You all know that nowadays all the companies
offer wellness discounts. These
companies offer this so that you
remain healthy and to stay healthy, the
company also gives you a little award of up to 30% here, that is, it
gives you a discount of up to 30%
on the renewal of the policy. Apart from this, if we
talk about other discounts, then here
you get a discount on credit card.
If your CIBIL score is good, then here the
company gives you a discount on the basis of CIBIL score.
Apart from this, let's talk
about voluntary copayment here, if you
opt for copay.  If it is 10% or 20% or 30%
or 40% or 50% then
you get a discount on the policy here
but copay means your premium will become
cheaper now but whenever a claim comes, whatever
your copay is,
you will have to share it in the claim amount
from your pocket.
Now let's talk about the waiting period,
you will get a waiting period here also from all the health insurance companies,
as the normal waiting period
which we call initial waiting period is
30 days,
for specific illness like cataract,
hernia, stone, fine or
obesity, you will get a waiting period of two years,
for those who have pre-existing diseases, the waiting period here is
three years, but
you can reduce it to 30 days by using riders,
similarly the
waiting period for maternity benefit will be two years here.  You will
get it but you can reduce it to
one year for the remaining waiting
period, you can follow the chart here,
apart from this there are many other
discounts available here, so whenever you
login to the policy,
all the
discounts that are applicable to you will be automatically applied on the basis of your documents,
okay now let us
talk about its important thing, that
how much is its premium because
I have told you everything, if I do
not tell you the premium then the video will be incomplete,
suppose a person whose age is 35 years here, he has a
wife and two children and
if we calculate the premium in Zone One, then
if you look at the basic plan in Zone One, then
his premium here will be
₹1 1964 plus GST, okay if
we add three riders in it,
Unlimited Claim Rider, Apart from this,
Unlimited No Claim Bonus Rider and Consumable,
adding these three riders, their
premium in Zone One will be
22246 plus GST, if all these things are same  If a
person goes to the same zone and
buys a policy, then his
premium will be Rs.
141419 plus GST in basic and Rs.
28 plus GST with rider. Now,
I will give you one more example here. Suppose a person
whose age is 60 years at present, his wife
's age is 58 years here, there are two family members, then
if we talk about their base plan, then
in zone one, their base plan will be
Rs.
7671 with GST. Whereas, if these
three riders which I told you are
taken with these riders, then their premium will be Rs.
8839 with three riders. So,
I have given you an overview of the premium here.
I hope you have understood these things. The
plan is very good, it is a completely
customized plan. You
can take this policy as per your requirement.
If you have any query related to the plan, you
can call us or comment.